<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: open source | tarashish dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://sunu.github.com/blog/categories/open-source/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sunu.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-28T01:09:14+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://sunu.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tarashish Mishra]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First step into the Open Source world]]></title>
    <link href="http://sunu.github.com/blog/2012/09/30/first-step-into-the-open-source-world/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-30T15:36:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sunu.github.com/blog/2012/09/30/first-step-into-the-open-source-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been wanting to contribute open source projects for quite some time. Contributing to existing open source projects is quite different from working on small projects of your own. I think the main problem I faced was the size of the repositories. The amount of code already there was always overwhelming. So I never went too far.</p>

<p>But now I have some good news to share. I have finally become a part (however small that is) of the open source movement. I have started contributing to <a href="http://moinmo.in/">MoinMoin</a>. As mentioned in their bitbucket <a href="https://bitbucket.org/thomaswaldmann/moin-2.0">repository</a>
<blockquote><p>MoinMoin is an easy to use, full-featured and extensible wiki software package written in Python. It can fulfill a wide range of roles, such as a personal notes organizer deployed on a laptop or home web server, a company knowledge base deployed on an intranet, or an Internet server open to individuals sharing the same interests, goals or projects.</p></blockquote></p>

<!--more-->


<p>At the time of writing this I have  got 3 pull requests accepted and resolved an <a href="https://bitbucket.org/thomaswaldmann/moin-2.0/issue/263/create-a-setup-less-moin-using-stuff-from">issue</a>. I mainly worked on creating a setup-less moin for both the standalone server and Google App Engine.</p>

<p>And this, I would say is my first step into the open source world :). All thanks to the help of <a href="http://twitter.com/thomasjwaldmann">Thomas Waldmann</a> in the irc channel. For all people wanting to get started with open source , just hang out in the irc of a project of your interest and there are always lovely people like Thomas who will help you out :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
